Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Photograph Collection, circa 1930-1993
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Yvar Mikhashoff Photograph Collection, circa 1930-1993
Mus. Arc. 1.5
Mikhashoff, Yvar
6 boxes
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The collection contains 423 indexed images and approximately 350 additional, un-indexed snapshots. The images include publicity shots, professional photographs and snapshots of Mikhashoff in rehearsal and performance, and snapshots from some of Mikhashoff's travels. Other people included in the images include noteworthy performers and composers, such as Aaron Copland, Virgil Thomson, Sylvano Bussotti, Henri Dutilleux, Giacinto Scelsi, Toru Takemitsu, Frederic Rzewski, Luis de Pablo, Henry Brant, John Cage, Milton Babbitt, Conlon Nancarrow, Nils Vigeland, and Poul Ruders.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Administrative Information
Acquisition Information
Gift of the estate of Yvar Mikhashoff, 1993
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
Collection has been digitized and is available in UB LIbraries Digital Collections.
Biographical Note
Yvar-Emilian Mikhashoff was born Ronald McKay in Troy near Albany, New York in 1941. He began piano studies with Betty Weir and Stanley Hummel in Albany. At the Eastman School of Music in 1959, he first took a major in composition and cello, then changed to piano studies with Armand Basile. In the 1961 academic year, he studied piano at the Juilliard School in New York City. He also had a career as a ballroom dancer from 1962-1965.
In 1964 Mikhashoff entered the University of Houston for studies in piano with Albert Hirsh. He earned a B.M. in 1967 and continued with graduate study in composition with Elmer Schoettle and obtained his M.M in 1968. It was during this period that McKay adopted his grandfather's name, Mikhashoff.
Receiving a Fulbright scholarship, he studied the music of the French Impressionists with Nadia Boulanger. After his return to the United States, McKay entered the University of Texas at Austin as a doctoral candidate in composition and studied with Hunter Johnson, Kent Kennan, Janet McGaughey and Karl Korte. He earned a Doctor of Musical Arts degree with a major in composition and a minor in literature in August 1973 and founded the Cambiata Soloists ensemble. In the Fall of 1973 Mikhashoff was appointed Assistant Professor at the State University of New York at Buffalo. Based in Buffalo until his death in 1993, Mikhashoff had an international performing career which led him to promote new music and American music around the world.
In addition to organizing many festivals and broadcasts of new music throughout the world, Mikhashoff was one of the founders of the North American New Music Festival and its director for 11 years. He commissioned works from such notable composers as John Cage, Lukas Foss, Otto Luening, Poul Ruders, James Sellars, Christian Wolff, and many others; he edited some works of Henry Cowell, Lejaren Hiller, Conlon Nancarrow, and Virgil Thomson. He recorded on the New Albion, Mode, RCA Victor, CRI, and Spectrum record labels. Yvar Mikhashoff's support of contemporary music continues today through the Yvar Mikhashoff Trust for New Music which was created by his estate to support composers and performers of new music.
Scope and Content Note
The Yvar Mikhashoff Photograph Collection contains 423 indexed images that chiefly document the professional life of pianist and composer Yvar Mikhashoff. The collection includes photographs by professional photographers such as Sarah Ainslie, Irene Haupt, Joann Miles, Annette Faltin, Lelli & Masotti, Wim Riemens, Gerda van der Veen, and Keith Gemerek. These photographs include publicity shots and images of Mikhashoff in performance or rehearsal. The snapshots in the collection provide a more casual look at Mikhashoff during his travels, performances, and with friends.
The list of composers included in the collection is indicative of Mikhashoff's involvement in contemporary music in America and internationally. The composers include Aaron Copland, Virgil Thomson, Sylvano Bussotti, Henri Dutilleux, Giacinto Scelsi, Toru Takemitsu, Frederic Rzewski, Luis de Pablo, Henry Brant, John Cage, Milton Babbitt, Conlon Nancarrow, Nils Vigeland, and Poul Ruders.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four series:
I. Photographs (133) and drawings (5) of Yvar Mikhashoff alone. Arranged in rough chronological order.
II. Photographs (285) of Yvar Mikhashoff with other people, other people without Mikhashoff, Mikhashoff alone when part of a photographic sequence, and scenes from Mikhashoff's travels. Arranged in rough chronological order.
III. Duplicates (unnumbered) and negatives.
IV. Approximately 350 snapshots with and without negatives, in 42 photo envelopes. Photographs of Yvar Mikhashoff were removed from this portion of the collection to be part of the indexed collection, Containers 1-4. Most of the remaining photographs are of landscapes and scenes encountered during Mikhashoff's travels to Czechoslovokia, Egypt, Israel, Jordan, and Mexico. Not indexed.
Container List
- Photographs and drawings of Yvar Mikhashoff alone, 1950-1993, I.; Containers 1-2, 5 drawings, 133 photographs
  Arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Yvar Mikhashoff silhouette, 1983, 1 black and white drawing; Eidem, Inger (Box 1, Item YM01-001)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff silhouette, 1983, 1 black and white drawing; Eidem, Inger (Box 1, Item YM01-002)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff portrait sketch, undated, 1 color drawing on Almeida program fragment; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-003)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff portrait drawing, undated, 1 black and white drawing; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-004)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff portrait, line drawing, April 8 1984, 1 black and white drawing; Jacobs, Bud (Box 1, Item YM01-005)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in Philadelphia, 1963, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-006)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff school photograph, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-007)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff high school graduation photograph, 1959, 1 black and white photograph; Frumkin Studio (Firm) (Box 1, Item YM01-008)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in late teens, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-009)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress, outside, May 1973, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-010)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in profile, casual photograph, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-011)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in striped shirt and tie, at piano with score of Richard Strauss's Sechs Lieder, May 1973, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-012)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in blue shirt in apartment, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-013)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress, outside, full figure, May 1973, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-014)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress, in front of trees, May 1973, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-015)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in profile at piano against black background, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-016)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in profile at piano against white block background, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-017)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black top at piano, facing camera, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-018)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress outside by columns, May 1973, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-019)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at keyboard in home studio, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-020)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at keyboard in home studio, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-021)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at desk in home studio, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-022)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at desk in home studio, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-023)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at keyboard in home studio, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-024)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff at keyboard in home studio, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-025)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white suit and shoes, outside, 1977, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-026)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white suit and shoes, seated in wicker chair, 1977, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-027)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in print shirt at piano, 1978, 1 black and white photograph; Riemens, Wim (Box 1, Item YM01-028)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white casual shirt facing towards camera, 1978, 1 black and white photograph; Riemens, Wim (Box 1, Item YM01-029)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black leather jacket, side view, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-030)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black leather jacket, back turned to camera, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-031)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black leather jacket, facing camera, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-032)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black turtleneck, facing camera, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-033)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black turtleneck, side view, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-034)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black turtleneck, far left, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-035)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black turtleneck, side view with piano to right, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-036)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black turtleneck, facing camera with piano to right, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-037)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black turtleneck, back to camera, leaning against piano, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-038)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black turtleneck, seated at piano facing camera, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-039)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black turtleneck, seated at piano, one hand raised, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-040)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black turtleneck, seated at piano, one hand raised, full size image, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-041)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in black turtleneck, with hands plucking strings of piano, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-042)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress, side view, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-043)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress, at side of piano facing camera, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-044)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress, seated at piano, 1979, 1 black and white photograph; Miles, Joann (Box 1, Item YM01-045)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt at piano with head thrown back, January 30 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Veen, Gerda van der (Box 1, Item YM01-046)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt at piano, hands of keyboard, face in anguish, January 30 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Veen, Gerda van der (Box 1, Item YM01-047)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff laying beneath piano, January 30 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Veen, Gerda van der (Box 1, Item YM01-048)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark suit, standing next to piano, looking towards ceiling, January 30 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Veen, Gerda van der (Box 1, Item YM01-049)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress as Monsieur Fred in Bussotti's opera, Le Racine, 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Lelli & Masotti (Firm) (Box 1, Item YM01-050)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress as Monsieur Fred in Bussotti's opera, Le Racine, 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Lelli & Masotti (Firm) (Box 1, Item YM01-051)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress as Monsieur Fred in Bussotti's opera, Le Racine, 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Lelli & Masotti (Firm) (Box 1, Item YM01-052)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal dress as Monsieur Fred in Bussotti's opera, Le Racine, 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Lelli & Masotti (Firm) (Box 1, Item YM01-053)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff standing on staircase outside building, 1980, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-054)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt and tie, profile, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-055)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in red jacket, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-056)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in red jacket and white trousers, standing before road sign, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-057)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in red jacket and white trousers in front of flower bed, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-058)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in red jacket and dark trousers, sitting on bale of hay at corner of W. 95th St. New York, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-059)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in sweater in a kitchen, 1985-07, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 1, Item YM01-060)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in formal attire, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Adams, Yura (Box 1, Item YM01-061)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt and tie, seated at piano, turned to his right to face camera, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-001)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt and tie, seated at piano, turned to his right to face camera, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-002)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white jacket and dark trousers at piano, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Faltin, Annette (Box 2, Item YM02-003)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white jacket in front of roughly textured wall, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Faltin, Annette (Box 2, Item YM02-004)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white jacket in front of roughly textured wall, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Faltin, Annette (Box 2, Item YM02-005)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white jacket in front of roughly textured wall, head shot, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Faltin, Annette (Box 2, Item YM02-006)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white jacket in front of roughly textured wall, contact sheet, undated, 1 black and white contact sheet; Faltin, Annette (Box 2, Item YM02-007)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white jacket at piano during performance, contact sheet, undated, 1 black and white contact sheet; Faltin, Annette (Box 2, Item YM02-008)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt and tie at piano, contact sheet, undated, 1 black and white contact sheet; Faltin, Annette (Box 2, Item YM02-009)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt and tie performing at piano, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-010)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt and tie performing at piano, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-011)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white jacket and dark trousers performing at Almeida Festival, with Bob Briggs, page-turner, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 2, Item YM02-012)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket and light trousers performing at piano, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Hauerbach, R. (Box 2, Item YM02-013)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket and light trousers performing while standing at piano, July 27 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-014)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket and light trousers performing at piano, July 27 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-015)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt and tie, standing outside, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-016)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket and white shirt, head shot, undated, 1 color photograph; Nowak, Edward L. (Box 2, Item YM02-017)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket and white shirt, head shot, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Nowak, Edward L. (Box 2, Item YM02-018)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket and tie, standing outside Albright-Knox Art Gallery, Buffalo, N.Y., undated, 1 black and white photograph; Loonan, Tom (Box 2, Item YM02-019)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket, striped trousers, seated with hand beneath chin, 1989, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 2, Item YM02-020)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket, seated, holding piece of music, 1989, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 2, Item YM02-021)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket, seated, holding piece of music, 1989, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 2, Item YM02-022)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket, seated, holding piece of music, 1989, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 2, Item YM02-023)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket, striped trousers, seated sideways at piano, 1989, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 2, Item YM02-024)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket, seated, 1989, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 2, Item YM02-025)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt and tie, seated at piano with eyeglasses propped on forehead, 1989, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 2, Item YM02-026)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white shirt and tie, performing at piano in home studio, 1989, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 2, Item YM02-027)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark suite and light trousers performing at piano, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Melzer, Manfred (Box 2, Item YM02-028)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark suit and light trousers performing at piano, unidentified page turner, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Melzer, Manfred (Box 2, Item YM02-029)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark suit and light trousers performing at piano, unidentified page turner, undated, 1 color photograph; Melzer, Manfred (Box 2, Item YM02-030)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark suite and light trousers performing at piano, undated, 1 color photograph; Melzer, Manfred (Box 2, Item YM02-031)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket and light trousers standing in hotel room, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-032)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket and light trousers with giant crab, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-033)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in white jacket and striped shirt seated in a restaurant with a menu, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-034)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket and tie in front of blackboard in classroom, undated, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-035)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket with carnation in lapel, performing Bussotti's Fogli at Almeida Festival, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 2, Item YM02-036)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket with carnation in lapel, sitting at piano with score of Bussotti's Fogli at Almeida Festival, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 2, Item YM02-037)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket with carnation in lapel at Almeida Festival, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Ainslie, Sarah (Box 2, Item YM02-038)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket leaning on back of chair, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 2, Item YM02-039)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket, head shot, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Gemerek, Keith (Box 2, Item YM02-040)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing behind upright piano, contact sheet, 1992, 1 black and white contact sheet; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-041)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing on a veranda, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-042)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing on a veranda, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-043)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing on a veranda beside large stone flower pot, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-044)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing on a veranda beside large stone flower pot, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-045)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket seated on stone bench next to flower pot, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-046)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket seated on stone bench next to flower pot, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-047)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket seated on stone bench next to flower pot, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-048)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket seated on stone bench next to flower pot, close up, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-049)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket seated on stone bench next to flower pot, close up, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-050)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket with Statue of Liberty in background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-051)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket with Statue of Liberty in background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-052)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket with Statue of Liberty in background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-053)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket with New York City skyline in background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-054)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket with New York City skyline in background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-055)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket with New York City skyline in background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-056)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket with New York City skyline in background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-057)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket with New York City skyline in background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-058)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket leaning on balustrade on veranda, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-059)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing before flower garden, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-060)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing before flower garden, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-061)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing next to bunting with water in background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-062)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing next to bunting with water in background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-063)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing next to a wall with the ship Queen Elizabeth 2 in the background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-064)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing next to a wall with the ship Queen Elizabeth 2 in the background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-065)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing next to a wall with the ship Queen Elizabeth 2 in the background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-066)
  - Yvar Mikhashoff in dark jacket standing next to a wall with the ship Queen Elizabeth 2 in the background, August 1993, 1 color photograph; Unidentified (Box 2, Item YM02-067)